Guide to the Scoville Family Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- Alice Scoville Barry Research Papers, 1870-2002
  - Research files
    - Beecher-Tilton trial notes
      - Testimonies
        - Sophie Scoville's comments, 1994 April 10 (Box 10, Folder 31)
        - Eunice Beecher and Theodore Tilton, Circa 1980s (Box 10, Folder 32)
        - Samuel Wilkeson, "Suffolk", Circa 1980s (Box 10, Folder 33)
        - Bessie Turner, Circa 1980s (Box 10, Folder 34)
        - Notes regarding alibi, Circa 1980s (Box 10, Folder 35)
        - Clifford E. Clark, Jr., Circa 1980s (Box 10, Folder 36)
        - Elizabeth Tilton cross examination and public opinion, Circa 1980s (Box 10, Folder 37-38)
        - Henry Ward Beecher's counsel, Circa 1980s (Box 10, Folder 39)
        - Theodore Tilton's counsel, Circa 1980s (Box 10, Folder 40)
        - Benjamin Tracy, Circa 1980s (Box 10, Folder 41)
        - Description of Susan B. Anthony, Circa 1980s (Box 10, Folder 42)
        - George Bell, Circa 1980s (Box 10, Folder 43)
        - Henry C. Bowen, Circa 1980s (Box 10, Folder 44)
        - Martha A. Bradshaw, cross examination, Circa 1980s (Box 10, Folder 45)
        - Kate Carey, Circa 1980s (Box 10, Folder 46)
        - Charles Cowley, Circa 1980s (Box 10, Folder 47)
        - Reverend Edward Eggleston, Circa 1980s (Box 10, Folder 48)
        - [Byram?] Halliday, Circa 1980s (Box 10, Folder 49)
        - John W. Harman, Circa 1980s (Box 10, Folder 50)
        - Isabella Oakley (Bella), Circa 1980s (Box 10, Folder 51)
        - Maria Ovington, Circa 1980s (Box 10, Folder 52)
        - Edward Ovington, 1983 (Box 10, Folder 53)
        - Sarah Putnam, Circa 1980s (Box 10, Folder 54)
        - Jackson S. and Bayter Schultz, Circa 1980s (Box 10, Folder 55)
        - Charles Storrs, Circa 1980s (Box 10, Folder 56)
        - William A. West, Circa 1980s (Box 10, Folder 57)
        - Victoria Woodhull, Circa 1980s (Box 10, Folder 58)
        - Thomas Shearman's apology to Tilton, Circa 1980s (Box 10, Folder 59)
        - Benjamin Tracy, Circa 1980s (Box 10, Folder 60)
        - Henry Ward Beecher, letter of contrition, Circa 1980s (Box 10, Folder 61)
        - Eunice's testimony at Church investigation trial by Mr. Ellinwood, July 14, 1874, Circa 1980s (Box 10, Folder 62)
      - Correspondence
        - Chris Heimsoth and Ed Ifkovic to Alice Scoville Barry, 2002 Jan 5-Feb 11 (Box 10, Folder 63)
        - Letters to Alice Scoville Barry regarding Henry Ward Beecher book, 1982 April 20-1994 April 17, undated (Box 10, Folder 64)
        - Correspondence between Anne Scoville Barry and Anne McCormick, 1986 June 22-1994 November 22, undated (Box 10, Folder 65)
        - #78 Comments and critiques by the Barry family and Elizabeth Wells, Circa 1990 (Box 10, Folder 66)
        - Tracy, Henry Ward Beecher's lawyer during the trial, Circa 1980s (Box 10, Folder 67)
        - John Porter's summation, Circa 1980s (Box 10, Folder 68)
        - The verdict of opinions, Circa 1980s (Box 10, Folder 69)
        - De Puy incident, murder of John Tucker, July 4, 1845, Circa 1980s (Box 10, Folder 70)
        - Letter to Tribune, Circa 1980s (Box 10, Folder 71)
        - Letter from Dr. Leonard Bacon, moderator of Church trial, Circa 1980s (Box 10, Folder 72)
        - News and courtroom notes, Circa 1980s (Box 10, Folder 73)
        - National Endowment for the Humanities (NEH) fellowship application, 1986–1989 (Box 10, Folder 74)
        - National Endowment for the Humanities (NEH) fellowship application, 1986–1989 (Box 10, Folder 75)
        - Annie Beecher Scoville, Circa 1980s (Box 10, Folder 76)
        - Aunt Fran's opinions and remarks, 1970s (Box 10, Folder 77)
        - J.K. Galbraith and Book of Lists, 1978 January (Box 10, Folder 78)
        - Catherine Gault letter, Circa 1980s (Box 10, Folder 79)
        - Elizabeth Tilton's letters from Marietta, Ohio, Circa 1980s (Box 10, Folder 80)
        - Original correspondence between Milton Rugoff and Alice Scoville Barry, 1981–1983 (Box 10, Folder 81)
        - Letters from Susan Howard, Circa 1980s (Box 10, Folder 82)
        - Henry Ward Beecher to the Congregation of the Plymouth Church, original, Circa 1980s (Box 10, Folder 83)
        - Katharine Beecher Park, now Mrs. Dudley Merrill, to Alice Scoville Barry regarding family opinion of Henry Ward Beecher, 1983 Dec 16 (Box 10, Folder 84)
        - Dr. Bacon and after church council his dog and Knave letter, and pieces in Independent (notes from Bacon Family Papers), 1989 (Box 10, Folder 85)
        - Correspondence between Henry Ward Beecher and Theodore Tilton, Circa 1980s (Box 10, Folder 86)
        - Bessie Turner's letter to Elizabeth Tilton, January 10, 1871, Circa 1980s (Box 10, Folder 87)
        - Theodore Tilton to Anna Dickinson 1871 Feb 23, transcription, Circa 1980s (Box 10, Folder 88)
        - Henry Ward Beecher to Eunice Beecher during and after church council, transcription, 1983 Aug 15 (Box 10, Folder 89)
        - Hattie Beecher quote in letter from Annie Howard to her father John Tasker Howard, Circa 1980s (Box 10, Folder 90)
        - Henry Ward Beecher's letters, Circa 1980s (Box 10, Folder 91)
        - William Lloyd Garrison to Theodore Tilton, Circa 1980s (Box 10, Folder 92)
        - John Howard Raymond to Henry Ward Beecher, Circa 1980s (Box 10, Folder 93)
        - Mark Twain on Henry Ward Beecher scandal, Circa 1980s (Box 10, Folder 94)
        - Correspondence between Theodore Tilton and Henry C. Bowen, Circa 1980s (Box 10, Folder 95)
        - Robert Bonner to Henry Ward Beecher, Circa 1980s (Box 10, Folder 96)
        - Theodore Tilton to Elizabeth Tilton, Circa 1980s (Box 10, Folder 97)
        - Dr. Richard S. Storrs to Henry Ward Beecher, 1872 Nov 2, Circa 1980s (Box 10, Folder 98)
        - Theodore Tilton to Henry Ward Beecher, Circa 1980s (Box 10, Folder 99)
        - Samuel Wilkeson to Theodore Tilton, 1871 Jan 11, Circa 1980s (Box 10, Folder 100)
        - Victoria Woodhull to Henry Ward Beecher, 1871 Nov 19 and 1872 Jun 3, Circa 1980s (Box 10, Folder 101)
        - Family reminesces of Mrs. Merwin Hart, descendent of John T. Howard, Circa 1980s (Box 11, Folder 1)
        - Edward Gray to Anne Scoville Barry, 1982 Jul 9 (Box 11, Folder 2)
        - Photocopies of letters to Annie Beecher Scoville from Hibben, 1926, her grandmother Eunice, 1886, and Henry Ward Beecher 1886, Circa 1980s (Box 11, Folder 3)
        - Correspondence of Henry Ward Beecher and Eunice during trial, Circa 1980s (Box 11, Folder 4)
        - Letters used during trial, 1983 (Box 11, Folder 5)
        - Correspondence of John Hooker, Isabella Hooker, Henry Ward Beecher, and Susan B. Anthony, Circa 1980s (Box 11, Folder 6)
        - Elizabeth Tilton to Theodore Tilton, Circa 1980s (Box 11, Folder 7)
        - John Hooker to Isabella Hooker, Florence to Isabella, Circa 1980s (Box 11, Folder 8)
        - Alice Barry's letter to Janet Barry regarding speech, copy, Circa 1980s (Box 11, Folder 9)
        - Henry Ward Beecher to Julia Merrill, photocopies, Circa 1980s (Box 11, Folder 10)
        - Henry Ward Beecher apology to Frank Moulton, photocopy, Circa 1980s (Box 11, Folder 11)
        - Letter from John Beecher to Alice Barry, 1980 Sep 7 (Box 11, Folder 12)
      - People
        - Henry Ward Beecher
          - Eunice Beecher notes, 1983–1991 (Box 11, Folder 13)
          - Handwritten chronology, 1870-1871, and a memo, Circa 1980s (Box 11, Folder 14)
          - Ignoring slanders, Circa 1980s (Box 11, Folder 15)
          - Statement, 1874, Circa 1980s (Box 11, Folder 16)
          - Letter of contrition, or apology, Circa 1980s (Box 11, Folder 17)
          - Photocopies of handwritten memos, Circa 1980s (Box 11, Folder 18)
          - Testimony in the investigating trial, Circa 1980s (Box 11, Folder 19)
          - Beecher family
            - Catherine Beecher's letter, Circa 1980s (Box 11, Folder 20)
            - George Beecher, Circa 1980s (Box 11, Folder 21)
            - Herbert Beecher, Circa 1980s (Box 11, Folder 22)
            - Harriet Beecher Stowe, Circa 1980s (Box 11, Folder 23)
            - Thomas K. Beecher, Circa 1980s (Box 11, Folder 24)
            - William Beecher, Circa 1980s (Box 11, Folder 25)
            - Edward Beecher, Circa 1980s (Box 11, Folder 26)
            - James Beecher (suicide - August 25, 1886), Circa 1980s (Box 11, Folder 27)
            - Mary Beecher Perkins, Circa 1980s (Box 11, Folder 28)
          - Beecher's children, Col. Henry and "Hattie Ben" Beecher, Circa 1980s (Box 11, Folder 29)
          - Beecher's parents, Lyman and Roxana, Circa 1980s (Box 11, Folder 30)
        - Henry Bowen
          - Henry Bowen versus Henry Ward Beecher, Circa 1980s (Box 11, Folder 31)
          - Hearing (expulsion) at Plymouth Church, March 2-3, 1876, Circa 1980s (Box 11, Folder 32)
        - Frank Moulton
          - Statement and his character (Box 11, Folder 33)
          - Testimony, Circa 1980s (Box 11, Folder 34)
          - Rough handling at the end of trial, Circa 1980s (Box 11, Folder 35)
          - Statement, August 21, 1874, for church investigation trial, Circa 1980s (Box 11, Folder 36)
          - Character, Circa 1980s (Box 11, Folder 37)
        - Theodore Tilton
          - For trial, Circa 1980s (Box 11, Folder 38)
          - Notes and newspaper clippings questioning trustworthiness (Box 11, Folder 39)
          - Letters to Dr. Bacon, 1874 April 4-10, Circa 1980s (Box 11, Folder 40)
          - "True Story" by Tilton, December 16, 1872 letter to a complaining friend, Circa 1980s (Box 11, Folder 41)
          - Insanity, Circa 1980s (Box 11, Folder 42)
          - Communist parade to honor Rossel, Circa 1980s (Box 11, Folder 43)
          - Testimony at Beecher-Tilton investigation, Circa 1980s (Box 11, Folder 44)
          - Accusation, summons, and objection to request for Bill of Particulars, and demand for legal trial, Circa 1980s (Box 11, Folder 45)
          - Notes on Tilton, Circa 1980s (Box 11, Folder 46)
          - Character and chronology, Circa 1980s (Box 11, Folder 47)
          - Theodore Tilton and Henry Bowen, Circa 1980s (Box 11, Folder 48)
          - Theodore Tilton and Henry Ward Beecher, Circa 1980s (Box 11, Folder 49)
          - Editorials in The Independent (notes and photostats), Circa 1980s (Box 11, Folder 50)
          - Lectures, marriage v. divorce February 8, 1872, Circa 1980s (Box 11, Folder 51)
          - Letter to a Complaining Friend, December 27, 1872, Circa 1980s (Box 11, Folder 52)
          - Sir Marmaduke's musings, written Oct 1871, published Nov 1871, Circa 1980s (Box 11, Folder 53)
          - Tit for Tat, by Victoria Woodhull, Circa 1980s (Box 11, Folder 54)
          - Tempest Tossed, by Tilton, Circa 1980s (Box 11, Folder 55)
          - Conspiracy with Frank Moulton and blackmail, Circa 1980s (Box 11, Folder 56)
          - Abuse of wife and children, Circa 1980s (Box 11, Folder 57)
          - Tilton's twist, including Elizabeth's letter: "To love is praiseworthy," et cetera, Circa 1980s (Box 11, Folder 58)
          - Motives, Circa 1980s (Box 11, Folder 59)
          - After the trial; Paris - poetry and death, Circa 1980s (Box 11, Folder 60)
          - Testimony in investigating committee, Circa 1980s (Box 11, Folder 61)
          - Newspaper accounts after Tilton's test, Circa 1980s (Box 11, Folder 62)
        - Elizabeth Tilton
          - Trial, Circa 1980s (Box 11, Folder 63)
          - Letters, retraction-to Moulton, Circa 1980s (Box 11, Folder 64)
          - Retraction accusation to Henry Ward Beecher, Circa 1980s (Box 11, Folder 65)
          - Testimony, Circa 1980s (Box 11, Folder 66)
          - Other letters, Circa 1980s (Box 11, Folder 67)
          - Two handwritten memos about Beecher and Tilton's reconciliation, Circa 1980s (Box 11, Folder 68)
          - "Confession", Circa 1980s (Box 11, Folder 69)
          - Elizabeth Tilton, Circa 1980s (Box 11, Folder 70)
        - Victoria Woodhull
          - Notes, Circa 1980s (Box 11, Folder 71)
          - Chronology, Circa 1980s (Box 11, Folder 72)
          - Chronology, Circa 1980s (Box 11, Folder 73)
          - "Final" version, 1989 (Box 11, Folder 74)
          - A medley, Circa 1980s (Box 11, Folder 75)
          - Her trial, 1872, Circa 1980s (Box 11, Folder 76)
          - Speech on free love, Steinwall Hall, November 21, 1871, Circa 1980s (Box 11, Folder 77)
          - Tilton's biography of Victoria, published in The Golden Age, 1871, Circa 1980s (Box 11, Folder 78)
          - Notes on article in Woodhull and Claflin's Weekly, November 2, 1872, 1988 (Box 11, Folder 79)
          - Notes, Circa 1980s (Box 11, Folder 80)
          - Response to Henry Bowen, Circa 1980s (Box 11, Folder 81)
          - Victoria in Washington, December 1870-January 1871, 1988 (Box 11, Folder 82)
          - Notecards referencing Tit for Tat, 1872, Circa 1980s (Box 11, Folder 83)
          - Victoria Woodhull and Tennie C. Claflin, Circa 1980s (Box 11, Folder 84)
        - Susan B. Anthony, Elizabeth Cady Stanton, Circa 1980s (Box 11, Folder 85)
        - Frank Carpenter, Circa 1980s (Box 11, Folder 86)
        - Horace Greeley, 1811-1872, huge funeral December 5, Circa 1980s (Box 11, Folder 87)
        - Henry W. Sage, Circa 1980s (Box 11, Folder 88)
        - Letters, Edna Dean Proctor to Henry Ward Beecher, 1871 Jan 10, notes, Circa 1980s (Box 11, Folder 89)
      - Events
        - Dr. Leonard Bacon's dog-knave speech to Yale Divinity students, circa April 1874, Circa 1980s (Box 11, Folder 90)
        - Council of Churches March 24-28, 1874 re: dropping of Tilton (October 31, 1873), Circa 1980s (Box 11, Folder 91)
        - John R. Howard's conversation with Dr. Storrs, 1873 Nov 7, Circa 1980s (Box 11, Folder 92)
        - Dropping Tilton from Plymouth, 1873 Oct 31, Circa 1980s (Box 11, Folder 93)
        - West's charges, Circa 1980s (Box 11, Folder 94)
        - "Silver Wedding" 25th anniversary of Plymouth, Circa 1980s (Box 11, Folder 95)
        - Tripartite agreement, 1872 Apr 2, Circa 1980s (Box 11, Folder 96)
      - Subjects
        - Free love, Circa 1980s (Box 11, Folder 97)
        - Spiritualism, Circa 1980s (Box 11, Folder 98)
        - Stirpiculture, Circa 1980s (Box 11, Folder 99)
        - Woman's suffrage, Circa 1980s (Box 11, Folder 100)
      - Mechanics and structure
        - Chapter headings, Forrest's bills, attempts at references, Circa 1980s (Box 12, Folder 1)
        - Parallel threads, 1871, Circa 1980s (Box 12, Folder 2)
        - Requisition at Yale, Sterling Library's Beecher Family, Circa 1980s (Box 12, Folder 3)
        - Critiques and comments of Alice Scoville Barry writing, Circa 1980s (Box 12, Folder 4)
      - Key quotes
        - "Nest-hiding", Circa 1980s (Box 12, Folder 5)
        - "Improper advances", Circa 1980s (Box 12, Folder 6)
        - Love babe, Circa 1980s (Box 12, Folder 7)
        - "The Good, the Bad, and the Beechers", Circa 1980s (Box 12, Folder 8)
      - Committee of investigation
        - Beecher letter to investigative committee, June 27-July, 1874, notes, Circa 1980s (Box 12, Folder 9)
        - Investigation committee - a rough commentary by Alice Scoville Barry, Circa 1980s (Box 12, Folder 10)
      - Library research
        - General, 1986–1988 (Box 12, Folder 11-12)
        - Amherst Library, 1983 (Box 12, Folder 13)
        - Connecticut Historical Society, 1987 (Box 12, Folder 14)
        - Library of Congress, 1981–1982 (Box 12, Folder 15)
        - Long Island Historical Society, 1987 (Box 12, Folder 16)
        - Princeton University Library, Circa 1980s (Box 12, Folder 17)
        - St. Bonaventure University, NY, Circa 1980s (Box 12, Folder 18)
        - Sterling Memorial Library, Beecher Family MSS, 1986 (Box 12, Folder 19)
        - The Stowe-Day Foundation, 1987 (Box 12, Folder 20)
        - Widener Library, Circa 1980s (Box 12, Folder 21)
        - Notes from trial record at the Widener Library, Circa 1980s (Box 12, Folder 22)
        - Yale University Library (slip with address), Circa 1980s (Box 12, Folder 23)
        - The Princeton University Library Chronicle, including Trollope's letter about Beecher scandal, 1981 (Box 12, Folder 24)
      - Press coverage
        - Public relations about Beecher's innocence, Circa 1990s (Box 12, Folder 25)
        - Christian Union and The Advance, Circa 1980s (Box 12, Folder 26)
        - The Golden Age, founded March 1871 by Tilton, Circa 1980s (Box 12, Folder 27)
        - The Independent, Circa 1980s (Box 12, Folder 28)
        - The Revolution, Circa 1980s (Box 12, Folder 29)
        - Sources for Beecher's speeches in England, Circa 1980s (Box 12, Folder 30)
        - Harper's Weekly summary of Trial as of June 5, 1875, Circa 1980s (Box 12, Folder 31)
        - A Circuit of the Continent: Account of a Tour Through the West and South, by Henry Ward Beecher, 1884 (Box 12, Folder 32)
        - Newspaper comments, Circa 1980s (Box 12, Folder 33)
        - Notes on press coverage of the trial, Circa 1980s (Box 12, Folder 34)
        - Press citations from trial coverage, Circa 1980s (Box 12, Folder 35)
        - Notes on newspaper coverage, Circa 1990 (Box 12, Folder 36)
        - The Star notes, Circa 1980s (Box 12, Folder 37)
      - Other notes
        - Alice Scoville Barry opinion of trial, 1981–1983 (Box 12, Folder 38)
        - Notes, Beecher's guilt or innocence, Circa 1980s (Box 12, Folder 39)
        - Uncontradicted Testimony with preface by Lyman Abbott, Circa 1980s (Box 12, Folder 40)
        - Altina Waller's thesis, 1982 February 20 (Box 12, Folder 41)
        - Notes and newspaper clippings, Circa 1980s (Box 12, Folder 42)
        - Evarts's summary, including St. Paul and the Viper, Circa 1980s (Box 12, Folder 43)
        - Copyright registration, 1985 March 21 (Box 12, Folder 44)
        - Transcribed letters, 1980s (Box 12, Folder 45)
        - Henry Ward Beecher cross examination, Circa 1980s (Box 12, Folder 46)
        - Letters used in the trial, Circa 1980s (Box 12, Folder 47)
        - Synopsis, Beecher and his accusers, 1980s (Box 12, Folder 48)
        - Trial notes, Circa 1980s (Box 12, Folder 49-56)
        - Index of subjects at trial, Circa 1980s (Box 12, Folder 57)
        - Opinions after the trial, Circa 1980s (Box 12, Folder 58)
        - Lucy Bowen's confession, April 25, 1863, Circa 1980s (Box 12, Folder 59)
        - Getting a commission for Harry Beecher and Henry Ward Beecher's statement (T.T.'s version and Wilkeson's version), Circa 1980s (Box 12, Folder 60)
        - Plot against Beecher conspiracy, notes on account by Lyman Abbott, Circa 1980s (Box 12, Folder 61)
        - Letter of contrition, Alice Scoville Barry synopsis, James Redpath, pistol scene, Circa 1980s (Box 12, Folder 62)
        - Peter MacLeod's summary of Porter's summary, Circa 1980s (Box 12, Folder 63)
        - Boston hearing of "trial," after the big trial circa 1875 November, Circa 1980s (Box 12, Folder 64)
        - Peekskill demonstration after the trial, Circa 1980s (Box 12, Folder 65)
  - Family papers
    - The Boys of '61, by Charles Carleton Coffin, 1888 (Box 13, Folder 1)
    - Children's drawings, 1978 (Box 13, Folder 2)
    - Alice Barry's letter to Mrs. John Beecher, 1980s (Box 13, Folder 3)
    - Print, "Beecher's American Soothing Syrup", Circa 1980s (Box 13, Folder 4)
    - Janet Barry's letters, family pictures, and genealogy (Tilton family), 1982 Oct 4 - 1987 Nov 17, undated (Box 13, Folder 5)
    - Beecher family reunion, 1983 June 25 (Box 13, Folder 6)
    - Letters from Burton Powers to Alice Scoville Barry, 1983 Jul 5-1987 Sep 22, undated (Box 13, Folder 7)
    - Alice Barry - Bibliography, credits, sources, personal biography, 1983 October (Box 13, Folder 8)
    - Plymouth Church and Church of the Pilgrims
      - Celebration of Henry Ward Beecher, 1986 June 18 (Box 13, Folder 9)
      - Henry Ward Beecher event to commemorate 100 years after his death and correspondence, 1986 June 26-1987 March 3, undated (Box 13, Folder 10)
    - Photographs of unidentified family members, 1954 Jan 6-22, undated (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - Wedding portrait, unidentified, Undated (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - Photograph of a room, possibly Anne Scoville Barry's, Undated (Box 6, Folder 8)